Olivia Hu

Hi! I'm Olivia. I am a sophmore studying a BFA in Communication
Design at Parsons School of Design with a background in graphic
design, web design, branding, and illustration. I would love to gain experience in designing content for brands and develop skills in UX/UI.

EMAIL:
PORTFOLIO:
INSTAGRAM
LOCATION:

oliviahu26@gmail.com www.imoliviahu.com @imoliviahu/@olivi__art New Jersey

AWARDS

- National Medal, Gold Key, Silver Key, and Honorable Mention from Scholastic Art and Writing Awards 2020
- High Merit Student Award from Celebrating Art Contest 2019 & 2020
- National Art Honor Society and Academic Honor Roll in High School
- Passed HSK(Chinese Proficiency Test) from Huaxia Sunday
 Chinese school of 9 years

EDUCATION

Parsons School of Design, The New School

Communication Design BFA (GPA: 3.9)

Introduction to Computer Science

(Harvard edX Online Course)

June 2020 - August 2020

August 2020 - present

EXPERIENCE

Youth and Sustainability | Brand and Web Designer March 2022 - April 2022

Designed the logo, colors, and chose typography for brand. Coded and designed the mobile website. Collaborated with a team to develop identity and content for brand.

Portfolio Editor and Photographer | Freelance

Assisted multiple art students by photographing and editing their artworks for art contests and developing college art portfolios.

Embolden Jewelry | Branding Designer

June 2020 - August 2020

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

Created three alternative logos, designed graphics, captured photos of products, and composed the layout of website/Instagram feed, while following the aesthetic, color palette, and message of the brand.

LANGUAGES

English
Chinese
Spanish
•••••••
••••••

Album Cover Designer and Video Animator | Freelance

2020 - 2021

Designed various versions of album covers and animated videos for song promotions following the client's style.

Starbucks | Barista

July 2021 - August 2021

Memorized and crafted a vast array of beverages in a fast-paced working environment while communicating with coworkers and customers to facilitate the best experience.

INTERESTS

- Drawing
- Movies
- Dancing
- Music
- Travel

SKILLS

- Adobe Photoshop, Premiere Pro, InDesign, After Effects, and Illustrator
- Typography, layout, color, and illustration
- · Photography, video-editing, and social media
- HTML, CSS, basic Javascript, and Figma
- Google Suite, Keynotes, Microsoft Office

- Creative
- Self-driven
- Problem-solving
- Organized
- Active listening
- Detail-oriented